const science_technology = [{ "question": "Immanuel Kant criticized Emanuel Swedenborg and termed him a âspook hunterâ.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "True", "choices": ["True", "False"] }, { "question": "Clouds are made up of these.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Water droplets and ice crystals", "choices": ["Carbon atoms", "Water droplets and ice crystals", "Oxygen ions", "Dust mites"] }, { "question": "This formation is a conical hill or mountain. It is formed by mantle material being pressed through an opening in the Earths crust.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "A volcano", "choices": ["A volcano", "A hill", "An earthquake", "A geyser"] }, { "question": "Japan suffers from this event very often. It is the sudden, light or violent movement of the earths surface caused by the release of energy in the earths crust.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Earthquake", "choices": ["Volcano", "Earthquake", "Tide", "Tsunami"] }, { "question": "It is the only continent that does not have land areas below sea level.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Antarctica", "choices": ["Australia", "South America", "Antarctica", "Arctica"] }, { "question": "It is the longest river in the world", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "The Nile", "choices": ["Themes", "The Amazon", "The Nile", "Danube"] }, { "question": "Why do travelers to La Paz, Bolivia, often become ill as soon as they arrive?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Because of the altitude", "choices": ["Because of the high temperature", "Because of the humidity", "Because of the soil quality", "Because of the altitude"] }, { "question": "In the US, why do we change our clocks on the daylight saving time dates in April and October?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "To conserve energy", "choices": ["To conserve energy", "To increase the hours of the day", "To extend the working day", "Because the tourist period in most countries starts in May"] }, { "question": "These are places of arid land with really low rainfall and high tempertures variation. Their vegetation is insignificant and the population of people and animals is very limited.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Deserts", "choices": ["Oceans", "Raiforests", "The equator", "Deserts"] }, { "question": "This is a gemstone made by fossilized tree sap that is at least 30 million years old.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Amber", "choices": ["Obsidian", "Amber", "Tourmaline", "Malachite"] }, { "question": "This is the largest island on Earth and one third of it is a national park.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Greenland", "choices": ["Greenland", "Madagaskar", "Australia", "Alaska"] }, { "question": "Which of these organs has no known function in the human body?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "appendix", "choices": ["tonsils", "appendix", "uvula", "pineal gland"] }, { "question": "The main function of this organ of respiration is to transport oxygen from the atmosphere into the bloodstream.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "lung", "choices": ["stomach", "diaphragm", "trachea", "lung"] }, { "question": "This gland is shaped like a butterfly and helps regulate energy in the body.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "thyroid", "choices": ["parathyroid", "thyroid", "adrenal", "thymus"] }, { "question": "The cerebellum section of the brain controls the fine movement and equilibrium, among other things.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "True", "choices": ["True", "False"] }, { "question": "These organs are very sensitive and often fail in people with very high blood pressure or diabetes.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "kidneys", "choices": ["pancreas", "kidneys", "ovaries", "lungs"] }, { "question": "Tooth enamel is the hardest substance in the body.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "True", "choices": ["False", "True"] }, { "question": "This is one of the first signs of pregnancy.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Missed period", "choices": ["Swollen Feet", "Missed period", "Hair loss", "Waddling"] }, { "question": "This doctor takes care of you and your baby during pregnancy.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Obstetrician", "choices": ["Psychologist", "Periodontist", "Obstetrician", "Pediatrician"] }, { "question": "What is the most common method of child birth?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Vaginal", "choices": ["Cesarean", "Vaginal", "Water birth", "In Vitro Fertilization"] }, { "question": "The mother determines the sex of the baby.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "False", "choices": ["False", "True"] }, { "question": "What are common side effects of pregnancy?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "All of the these", "choices": ["Stretch marks", "Morning Sickness", "All of the these", "Weight gain"] }, { "question": "How far along are you approximately, when you feel the baby move for the first time?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "20 weeks", "choices": ["10 weeks", "35 weeks", "2 weeks", "20 weeks"] }, { "question": "What is suggested that you not do several hours before you go into labor?  It could get you embarrassed.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Eat food", "choices": ["Eat fish", "Have sex", "Talk on the phone", "Eat food"] }, { "question": "What is also delivered along with the baby or immediately after its birth?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Placenta", "choices": ["Feet", "Shoulders", "Placenta", "Handbook"] }, { "question": "These small bodies are considered left overs from the formation of the Solar system some 4.6 billion years ago.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Asteroids", "choices": ["Comets", "Stars", "Planets", "Asteroids"] }, { "question": "These are lumps of ice and dust.  When they get close enough to the Sun they gradually evaporate.  Jets of gas and dust create long tails that people can see from Earth.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Comets", "choices": ["Asteroids", "Comets", "UFOs", "Stars"] }, { "question": "This planet is slightly smaller than Earth and its closest neighbor (excluding the Moon).", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Venus", "choices": ["Venus", "Uranus", "Mars", "Saturn"] }, { "question": "This planet is has the largest  group of moons - 31, but it is best known for its ring system.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Saturn", "choices": ["Neptune", "Mars", "Saturn", "Venus"] }, { "question": "This planet of the Solar System was named after a Greek god of the sea and earthquakes. The name is actually the Roman translation of the gods name.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Neptune", "choices": ["Mercury", "Neptune", "Pluto", "Uranus"] }, { "question": "As this is the closest planet to the Sun, its temperatures at the surface range between -300 and 800 F (hot enough for lead to melt).", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Mercury", "choices": ["Neptune", "Mercury", "Pluto", "Venus"] }, { "question": "The surface of this planet is unique, it is the only one which has water in large quantities.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Earth", "choices": ["Saturn", "Pluto", "Earth", "Mars"] }, { "question": "Which Solar System celestial bodys revolution around the Sun takes 248 years?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Pluto", "choices": ["Saturn", "Pluto", "Neptune", "Uranus"] }, { "question": "This is the largest planet in our solar system. It is most famous for its Great Red Spot.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Jupiter", "choices": ["Mars", "Neptune", "Saturn", "Jupiter"] }, { "question": "Miranda, Ariel, Umbriel, Titania, Oberon, Caliban, and Sycorax are names of the icy moons of this planet.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Uranus", "choices": ["Uranus", "Jupiter", "Saturn", "Venus"] }, { "question": "The popular chat room abbreviation asl or a/s/l stands for age, sex, and location.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "True", "choices": ["True", "False"] }, { "question": "An icon or animation to represent a participant used in Internet chat and games is referred to as this.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Avatar", "choices": ["Bitmap", "Cookie", "Applet", "Avatar"] }, { "question": "If you and I are chatting over the Internet and I write LOL, that means that I am doing this.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Laughing", "choices": ["Crying", "Laughing", "Sleeping", "Eating"] }, { "question": "The terms smiley and emoticon refer to one and the same thing.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "True", "choices": ["True", "False"] }, { "question": "http://www.123facts.com/ is referred to as this.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "URL", "choices": ["TCP", "WAP", "URL", "USB"] }, { "question": "One of the following pairs (chat abbreviation - its  meaning) is wrong.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "TTYL - To Tell You a Lie", "choices": ["BRB - Be Right Back", "ATM - At The Moment", "TTYL - To Tell You a Lie", "TIA - Thanks In Advance"] }, { "question": "One of these things will not help you to get in touch with your neighbours PC.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Cache server", "choices": ["Hub", "Router", "Cache server", "Network card"] }, { "question": "If they call me a newbie then I am new to the Internet; and/or new to the subject in general.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "True", "choices": ["False", "True"] }, { "question": "In chat jargon, the emoticon  [8-] refers to this person.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Frankenstein", "choices": ["Elvis", "Ronald Regan", "Frankenstein", "The Pope"] }, { "question": "The medical term cardio, deriving from a Greek word, refers to which organ of the human body?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Heart", "choices": ["Brain", "Liver", "Lungs", "Heart"] }, { "question": "The term arthro is of Greek origin. It refers to which part of the body?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Joint", "choices": ["Head", "Skin", "Bone", "Joint"] }, { "question": "Gastro is a common medical prefix, derived from the Greek word gastros which means what?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Stomach", "choices": ["Gas", "Brain", "Cell", "Stomach"] }, { "question": "The word hepato, which derives from Greek, refers to the kidney.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "False", "choices": ["False", "True"] }, { "question": "Erythrocytes are a type of blood cells, consisting mainly of hemoglobin. What does the word erythro mean?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Red", "choices": ["Red", "Knowledge", "Cell", "White"] }, { "question": "The term thrombo, which comes from Greek, refers to a blood clot.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "True", "choices": ["False", "True"] }, { "question": "The word adeno, deriving from Greek, refers to which to what body part?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Gland", "choices": ["Flesh", "Brain", "Gland", "Kidney"] }, { "question": "The two terms nephro and ren both refer to the kidneys.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "True", "choices": ["True", "False"] }, { "question": "Onco, coming from the Greek word onkos refers to what?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Tumor", "choices": ["Ear", "Nerve", "Eye", "Tumor"] }, { "question": "The food colorants, cochineal and carmine, are made from what?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "A kind of insect", "choices": ["Frogs", "A kind of insect", "FDC Red Dye #40", "None of these"] }, { "question": "Jell-O, the popular gelatin dessert, is made in part, from what?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Bones and hides", "choices": ["Bones and hides", "Red ants", "None of these", "Horses and cows hooves"] }, { "question": "Twinkies, the sponge cake with creamy filling, created by Hostess, have an indefinite shelf life.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "False", "choices": ["True", "False"] }, { "question": "Which of these statements, related to the effects of eating turkey, is true?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "None of these", "choices": ["Turkey slows your metabolic rate which makes you drowsy", "A turkey makes you sleepy as it contains the natural sedative L-tryptophan", "Increased blood flow to the gastrointestinal tract makes one drowsy", "None of these"] }, { "question": "The traditional Japanese dish, sushi, is always made with raw fish.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "False", "choices": ["True", "False"] }, { "question": "What food results in negative calories when eaten?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "All of these", "choices": ["Carrots", "Celery", "All of these", "Radishes"] }, { "question": "Chop Suey, a pasta dish consisting of short noodles, was originally made and served in which country?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "USA", "choices": ["Thailand", "USA", "China", "Vietnam"] }, { "question": "Gatorade, a non-carbonated sports drink, was invented by researchers at the University of Florida and named in honor of the Florida Gators, the schools football team.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "True", "choices": ["False", "True"] }, { "question": "In 2003, the FDA issued a warning about a possible connection between green onions and which disease?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Hepatitis A", "choices": ["None of these", "Gall stones", "Hepatitis A", "Cancer"] }, { "question": "In the USA, the color of the plastic tags, used to seal bread bags, indicates on what day the loaves were baked.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "True", "choices": ["True", "False"] }, { "question": "Death of heart tissues due to loss of blood supply correctly describes the condition known as Myocardial Infarction.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "True", "choices": ["True", "False"] }, { "question": "This progressive generative disease of the brain results in loss of cognitive ability and uncontrolled movements, called chorea, the Greek word for dance.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Huntingtons Disease", "choices": ["Alzheimers Disease", "Myasthenia Gravis", "Multiple Sclerosis", "Huntingtons Disease"] }, { "question": "Which of these is best describes the cause of Parkinsons disease?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "A decrease in a neurotransmitter", "choices": ["A brain injury", "Changes in the myelin sheath of the neuron", "Decreased blood flow to the brain", "A decrease in a neurotransmitter"] }, { "question": "If your physician tells you that you have Presbycusis due to the normal process of aging, he may suggest that you need which of these?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Hearing aid", "choices": ["Dentures", "Glasses", "A wheelchair", "Hearing aid"] }, { "question": "Which of these medical terms means difficulty in swallowing.", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "dysphagia", "choices": ["dyspepsia", "dysuria", "dyspnea", "dysphagia"] }, { "question": "Does the condition known as Hypoglycemia imply that blood sugar levels in the body are too high?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "No", "choices": ["Yes", "No"] }, { "question": "If you have hyperthyroidism, your body is overproducing what hormone?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Thyroxine", "choices": ["Estrogen", "Thyroxine", "Glucagon", "Thyrocalcitonin"] }, { "question": "Which of these most accurately describes the medical term, necrosis?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Death of living tissue", "choices": ["Irregular heartbeat", "Death of living tissue", "Decrease in white blood cells", "Liver damage"] }, { "question": "Your physician has ordered an electroencephalogram (EEG), the graphic recording of the electrical activity of what organ?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "Brain", "choices": ["Muscles", "Liver", "Heart", "Brain"] }, { "question": "In the US, what was the average street cost of a lid (3/4 ounce bag) of marijuana in the mid 1970s?", "category": "science_technology", "answer": "$15.00", "choices": ["$20.00", "$10.00", "$15.00", "$5.00"] }]